# **KYLE BINDER**

I am a quantitative team lead with a versatile skillset lying at the intersection of statistics, economics, and data science. I currently manage a team of quantitative analysts that builds and maintains production-level econometric models for the Federal Reserve System. I have experience communicating complex market and model concepts to senior stakeholders, developing analytical tools (including software packages and applications), and publishing research in peer-reviewed academic journals.

## **I** CURRENT POSITION

2022present

#### Supervision Manager

Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago

Chicago, IL

- Lead of the Federal Reserve System's commercial real estate stress test modeling team
- Manage team of economists, quant analysts, and data scientists at FRB Chicago

2019-2022

#### **Lead Quantitative Specialist**

Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago

Chicago, IL

- Deputy, then Acting Lead of the Federal Reserve System's commercial real estate stress test modeling team
- · Research and analytics in US commercial real estate finance

2016-2019

#### **Senior Quantitative Specialist**

Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago

Chicago, IL

• R&D, production, and monitoring for wholesale credit risk supervisory models



#### **EDUCATION**

2016

#### **Texas A&M University**

Ph.D. in Applied and Agricultural Economics

Ocllege Station, TX

• Focus on time series modeling, resource and energy economics

2012

## **Centre College**

B.S. in Financial Economics

O Danville, KY



## **PUBLICATIONS**

2021

## Bank exposure to commercial real estate and the Covid-19 pandemic

Chicago Fed Letter No. 463

Binder, K., E. Greenwald, S. Schulhofer-Wohl, and A. Drexler

## **CONTACT INFO**

kylebinder90@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/kyle-binder

kylebinder.netlify.app

### SKILLS

Background in econometric and statistical modeling, analytical tool development

Leadership and project management of model development tasks and workflows

Communicating technical topics to non-technical audiences

Highly skilled in R, SQL

Experienced in Python, Stata, SAS, Unix bash scripting

User and proponent of Git, Rmarkdown

> This resume was made with the R package pagedown.

> > Last updated on 2022-12-08.

2020		The role of temporal dependence in factor selection and forecasting oil prices Empirical Economics 58 (3): 1185-1223 Binder, K.E., M. Pourahmadi, and J.W. Mjelde
2018		Projecting impacts of carbon dioxide emission reductions in the U.S. electric power sector: evidence from a data-rich approach Climatic Change 151 (2): 143-155 Binder, K.E. and J.W. Mjelde
2017	•	Fuel inventory and price relationships in the U.S. electrics power sector under regulatory and market change Journal of Regulatory Economics 51 (2): 197-219 Binder, K.E. and J.W. Mjelde
2016		Price interaction in state-level renewable energy credit trading programs The Electricity Journal 29 (4): 15-21 Binder, K.E., J.W. Mjelde, and R.T. Woodward
		PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE
2012- 2016		Graduate Assistant Texas A&M University
2011	•	Intern Oak Ridge National Laboratory  ◆ Oak Ridge, TN
	Ö	ACTIVITIES AND AWARDS
2019	•	President's Award for Excellence Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago
2018	•	Making a Difference Award Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago
2017	•	Outstanding PhD Dissertation Southern Agricultural Economics Association
2016	•	Top PhD Dissertation Texas A&M Agricultural Economics Department
2015		Harris Fellowship for Outstanding Undergraduate Teaching Texas A&M University
2008- 2011	•	Men's Basketball Team Centre College
2008- 2011	•	Academic Honor Roll Southern Collegiate Athletic Conference